<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://blog.jpanderson.dev/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://blog.jpanderson.dev/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-09T08:03:09+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.jpanderson.dev/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jon Anderson Personal Blog</title><subtitle>An open book journal for my thoughts</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Turning 29 on 2/9 (U.S.)</title><link href="https://blog.jpanderson.dev/2021/02/09/turning-29-on-2-9-u-s.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turning 29 on 2/9 (U.S.)" /><published>2021-02-09T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-09T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.jpanderson.dev/2021/02/09/turning-29-on-2-9-u-s</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.jpanderson.dev/2021/02/09/turning-29-on-2-9-u-s.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;today-is-my-birthday&quot;&gt;Today is my Birthday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow, today is my birthday. What a nightmare 2020 was, not even just the pandemic. It started off well enough (vacation to New Orleans and making some new, amazing friends) and is ending…well, here. I want shallowly reflect on the past year and what hopefully next year and beyond look like for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;last-year&quot;&gt;Last Year&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lord last year was a struggle. On the one hand, really cool things happened. I got to onboard my first hire and she’s doing amazing now (even just got a promotion). I helped lead the team I was on to do some pretty impressive things around deploy automation, audits, and code record keeping for a growing Engineering organization. I loved the work we got to do. That said, work also became a giant emotional drain for me, sucking me into a void of selfishness and spite. I hit a breaking point in mid-August and started actively looking for jobs. I found my new job via a &lt;em&gt;promoted tweet&lt;/em&gt;. I saw this neat company, FireHydrant, and immediately looked for job openings. They had a perfect one for me. I applied and a couple of months later I got the job. I’ve gotten to move from projects and people that drained my soul to doing really cool things at the application layer again with some incredibly supportive folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sort of a hobby, but still programming. I wrote an Elixir library, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lirossarvet/honeylixir&quot;&gt;Honeylixir&lt;/a&gt;, for sending data to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.honeycomb.io&quot;&gt;Honeycomb&lt;/a&gt; because I wasn’t thrilled with some of the prior art I could find. I did it about 80% because I wanted to write some Elixir and really like Honeycomb and 20% because I was thinking of applying for a Honeycomb job. I’m still pretty proud of it. I know it could use a little love to improve readability, but it gave me a huge chance to learn and experiment with GenServers and other state things in erlang/Elixir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So professionally it was a mixed bag: lots of learning and pain at one spot while also joy and mentorship and maturity by moving on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, though… Hm. Let’s talk relationships with other people first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year more-or-less started with a planned trip to New Orleans with some college-ish (it’s a long story) friends. It was a damn blast. We ate delicious food, got drunk, walked around and saw so much history, and it was just ultimately a very delightful time. Didn’t realize it would be the end of an era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I effectively moved in with some new friends I’d made over Twitter in, oh, January and met in-person in February. So from March until June I lived with them about three hours from all my friends in Seattle. It was a weird, rough transition. I would’ve been worse off, or less responsible, had I stayed isolated in Seattle. I’m eternally grateful they let me stay so long with them. Finally got an apartment of my own in June where I’ve been since. More space, got a cat, all pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I’ve also had swaths of time where I miss my friends there dearly. A common refrain of adulthood is that it’s much harder to keep friends you don’t work with. This gets even harder when many are marrying, having kids, and a pandemic is happening. I sometimes wonder if I’d be drifting as much if social isolation hadn’t lined up with me needing to leave, but I’ll never know. It feels right, though, considering I talk to maybe two friends from high school and two or three from college. Long-term friendships are apparently difficult for me if I’m not constantly seeing you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little more internally/personally, 2020 was fucking awful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve suffered from body dysmorphic disorder for, what I think is, a significant chunk of my life. Diagnosed only since 2019. Isolation did me no favors here. Stress and other things led me to &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; gain the weight I so feared I already had and made me unworthy. I’m officially 65 pounds heavier than I was at the start of the pandemic. While I’ve always hidden my body from myself (always sit with a blanket even at home, hunched inward as much as possible to compress myself, other things…), it’s gotten much worse now. Where before I would avoid maybe 1 in 10 social events because I felt so gross, I found myself now avoiding what felt like 1 in 3 of very limited social interactions. The effect is so much stronger now and all the more painful given the limited chances to go out in public or just be around people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alcohol abuse also hit a tremendous peak in 2020 going into 2021. I was easily drinking 8 bottles of wine a week (or 40 standard drinks in a period when the max should be 14) with some weeks definitely higher. There was a brief period of very moderated drinking from March to May (neat how that coincides with living with other people huh), but then took off again in a hurry. There’s more to probably unpack here, but just…yeah. 2020 was incredibly bad for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-year-moving-forward&quot;&gt;This year moving forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to make 2021 my year. Mainly because it’s my 29th year of life starting on 2/9/92. It feels…auspicious, like I should make the most of it, a hidden chance that not everyone gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve joined a site called &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinmonument.com&quot;&gt;Monument&lt;/a&gt; that I’ve been using for about a month now for my alcohol abuse. I’m not sure if it’s a honeymoon-like phase, but I’ve gone from so much wine down to maybe two bottles in a week and only on the weekends. I’ll be working with a doctor and a therapist, but my rough goal is to consistently find myself having no more than 6 drinks per week. I may stick with the “FDA max” (these studies are probably questionable and many paid for by the alcohol industry) of 2 drinks per day just for ease of tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started walking every day, at least 30m. My unwritten goal is to close the green exercise ring every day I’m able to. With it being winter, I’d have to buy some heavier winter clothes for certain days so on those I don’t make it for sure. Having bought a few rounds of large and XL clothes (underwear, sweats, shirts) to fit into, I’m not sure I can emotionally handle warmer winter weather gear in those sizes. Going onward for fitness, I’m also on a waiting list to get a rowing machine. I’ve always enjoyed them at gyms, and figured since so many break down to be smaller for storage, it would be a good fitness machine I could move with pretty easily. I should &lt;em&gt;hopefully&lt;/em&gt; get that by mid-March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited for work, honestly. I haven’t felt excited about work in a while, not at such a visceral level. I know it’s at least partly a honeymoon phase (it’s only month three after all), but damn if it isn’t nice. It’s like I can feel the burnout slowly evaporating from me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I intend to complete an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nerves-project.org&quot;&gt;Elixir Nerves&lt;/a&gt; Raspberry Pi weather station for my apartment. I wanted something that could give me temperature, humidity, and AQI (or at lest 2.5 PPM). I think I finally have all the sensors and connectors I need. The trick is going to be putting it together, some hopefully quick-ish coding, then somehow getting a case for it. The case is the part I’m most stressed about, but I’ve got to not let that stop me from doing the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should schedule time with my friends to talk, even just once every three months. I doubt I will, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll continue saving up to maybe move as well as for a down payment. I can’t explain why my mind has been stuck on Minneapolis as a place to move for the past few months, but it has. A city I’ve visited once as a teenager has indelibly stuck in my brain for a decade. Feels like I owe it at least consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also continue snuggling my cat as he is adorable curled up beside me while I write this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure there are more things I intend for this year, probably even more reflective posts if I can. There’s a lot of thoughts swirling in my head about how I’m not who I want to be or not the version of me I think I can be and how I stop myself from getting there. And also is it a healthy (e.g., growth mindset, skilled analysis of rightness for myself, empathy) vision for myself. But that’s for another time because it’s almost midnight and my birthday and I’m tired.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="alcohol" /><category term="review" /><category term="reflections" /><summary type="html">Today is my Birthday</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Where is home?</title><link href="https://blog.jpanderson.dev/personal/2020/09/12/what-i-want.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where is home?" /><published>2020-09-12T04:09:55+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-12T04:09:55+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.jpanderson.dev/personal/2020/09/12/what-i-want</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.jpanderson.dev/personal/2020/09/12/what-i-want.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;where-is-home&quot;&gt;Where is Home?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working through therapy for a while now. Two common themes recur: I simultaneously hate myself and have no idea who I am or what I want in life. While the first is a very long road to tread, I can try to figure out what a Good Life looks like for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I keep thinking about is where to put down roots; where might I want to buy a home and live for a long time rather than a couple of years. I really liked living in Kansas City, MO: it’s far enough from my family to be annoying for them to show up but close enough I can go back for an emergency or a weekend, the community is pleasant, lovely architecture, an almost-liberal hold in a very conservative state. Seattle, WA was also great: beautiful surroundings, liberal hold in a kinda blue state (we’ll get back to that), lovely architecture if you know where to look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past six months or so, I’ve been living in the Tri-Cities, WA. It’s a different kind of place. There’s some of Washington’s nature ideals. It’s a desert so it’s gorgeous in a way that’s very different from the lush forests and mountains of Seattle. It’s also very new, which is something I didn’t expect to…not appeal to me in the same way. While a lot of construction in Seattle is very new, Seattle itself is old (for America). It was a large city before the 20th century, burned down, and rebuilt with some uniqueness. The Tri-Cities isn’t that. There’s a bit of history, but settlement here doesn’t really pick up until early-to-mid 20th century with the Manhattan Project and its aftermath really driving population. It’s also a pretty conservative area, something I struggle with quite frankly. And, it’s far from my family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a high schooler, I looked at a few places to go to college: Washington University of St. Louis, University of Arkansas (where I went), University of Missouri - Kansas City, University of Washington, and University of Minnesota. These were the five I cared most about looking through and understanding. I landed at Arkansas because it was 4 hours away from most of my family and was a new start. UMKC as similarly a new start. I moved to Seattle at 24 and was there until I was 28, moving to the Tri-Cities. These have always been the places I looked to most, with job opportunities driving me from place to place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COVID-19, for all it’s terribleness especially in the States, has shown me I can work pretty well remotely, though. I’ve learned new ways of collaborating and self-motivating. Admittedly, I miss the office; I miss the simple camaraderie of bumping into people, the socialization and knowing you can go out with them after work and it’s a way to build friendships. But the remoteness has shown I could in theory live and work almost anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minneapolis keeps tickling at the back of my mind as a place to set down roots, a place to go. It’s the Midwest, so I’d be pretty used to whatever it can throw, though certainly more harsh winters than KCMO or my hometown offered. The architecture is what I know and love. Minneapolis is also a fairly liberal city with Minnesota being a somewhat liberal state. I think it’s a place I could maybe call home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure. I wouldn’t know anyone there, and I love my friends I’ve made in Washington. I’m drawn to them; I love them. I don’t know if I could actually start basically over again, at least for people to do casual dinners with or to grab a drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s a thing I’m thinking about as I get to a point where I’d like to dig roots in deep in a place I want to call home.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">Where is Home?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction and Struggles</title><link href="https://blog.jpanderson.dev/2020/08/16/my-introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction and Struggles" /><published>2020-08-16T02:30:55+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-16T02:30:55+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.jpanderson.dev/2020/08/16/my-introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.jpanderson.dev/2020/08/16/my-introduction.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;life-has-been-rough&quot;&gt;Life has been rough&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not really sure what it is. My life is…fine? In theory. It’s really fine. I’ve got great friends. I’ve got a nice living space. I have a (very needy) cat who is adorable. He deserves all the pets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But lordy lou. For the past couple of years, I’ve really struggled with…well, just straight up hating myself like a boss. That often leads to me drinking. I will frequently alternate between a couple of weeks of excessive drinking (two bottles of wine a day, on average) and a couple of weeks of abstinence. At least part of why I drink is to blackout. Reason: sometimes I think “I don’t really want to be alive right now, like not have to live through this at the moment,” and so I drink to not be alive, not really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m so tired of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started going to therapy (again), but this time with a stronger focus on substance abuse. My first appointment with her went pretty well for an intake. I’m glad it didn’t take her long to realize that something I struggle with is not feeling like I have an identity; I feel like a mirror, reflecting people back to them, but never anything of my own. I’m not sure where we’ll go from there, but the next couple of weeks will hopefully help me figure out if she’s a good therapy fit for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this is what makes me…me? A man full of depression and self-loathing who doesn’t know who he is and drinks to forget that fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve thought of going abstinent, of going sober entirely. I can’t decide if I don’t want to because I actually enjoy drinking and would like to find a way to do so responsibly or if I’m just an addict who wants his fix. I &lt;em&gt;imagine&lt;/em&gt; the answer is somewhere in the middle, but I don’t know yet. I’d like to try a few different plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m incredibly grateful to my friends who’ve been here for me. I even got help cleaning up my disaster of an apartment as a way to help unfuck my habitat a lot. I’m slowly fucking it up again, but I think I can stop the cycle. I think I’m prepared to make some shifts and adjustments that I’ve been mentally prepping for the past week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate myself, and I’d really like to stop.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Life has been rough</summary></entry></feed>